《非常人贩2》
I'm so sorry. Can you help me? My tyre...
真对不起 可以帮我吗? 我的车胎...
Sorry. I have an appointment. I don't like to be late.
不好意思 我有约会 我不喜欢迟到
Well, would you rather be late or dead?
你是喜欢迟到还是翘辫子呢?
- You don't want to do this. - Step out of the car.
- 你不想这么做的 - 下车
Whoo! Let's go, fellas!
上吧 大伙!
Come on, baby! Yes!
快点 宝贝! 好耶!
Take it easy. The car's brand-new.
轻点 车是全新的
- No problem, buddy. I got this. - Baby, let's ride. Time to go.
- 没问题 我有这个 - 宝贝 开车吧 该走了
- Your parents know the company you keep? - Shut up.
- 你父母晓得你交这种朋友吗? - 闭嘴
- This shit ain't working. - It's coded.
- 发不动 - 有设定密码
- What's the code? - I can't give you that.
- 密码多少? - 我不能给你
We'll have to beat it out of you. Get out the car.
我们只好逼你招了 下车
Come on, man. What you got for me?
来吧 老兄 看你有何本事
Kick your ass!
去你的!
Hold on.
等一下
It just came out of the dry cleaner's.
西装才刚从干洗店取回来
Hands up. Stop moving or I will shoot you.
手举起来 别走动 否则我会开枪
Don't you have homework to do?
你没功课要做吗?
- Why don't you go and do it? - OK. I'm sorry.
- 为何不去做呢? - 好的 对不起
Late.
迟了
Hey! Hey!
嘿! 嘿!
- The game, the game, the game! - What's the first rule on entering a man's car?
- 游戏 游戏 游戏! - 上别人车的第一条规矩是什么?
- Respect a man's car, a man respects you. - Rule number two.
- 尊重别人的车 别人就会尊重你 - 第二条
- Greet the man. Good afternoon, Frank. - Good afternoon, Jack.
- 跟车主打招呼 午安 法兰克 - 午安  杰克.
- Can we play the game? - I should think you'd be tired after school.
- 可以玩游戏吗? - 我想你放学后很累
- You're afraid I'm gonna win. - You'll be too worn out to do your homework.
- 你是怕我会赢 - 我怕你太累了无法做作业
- It's Friday. I don't have any homework. - In that case, the game.
- 今天是星期五 根本没作业 - 果真那样就来玩吧
- Yes! - But first, what's the third rule of the car?
- 好耶! - 不过前提 第三条规矩是什么?
Good.
很好
Five points. I'm white, I'm round, but I'm not always around.
答对得五分 既白又圆 但不一定都在
- A tennis ball? - Tennis balls are yellow.
- 网球? - 网球是黄色的
Four points.
答对得四分
Sometimes I'm half, sometimes whole. Sometimes a slice is all you know.
有时一半 有时完整 有时只有一小片
- A loaf of bread? - No.
- 一条面包? - 不对
Three points. Sometimes I'm light, sometimes dark. Sometimes I'm both.
答对得三分 有时亮 有时暗 有时两者皆是
- I know. A light buIb. - No.
- 我知道了 是电灯泡 - 不对
- A pizza! - No.
- 披萨! - 不对
Audrey. Audrey! Stop walking away from me.
奥黛莉 奥黛莉! 别走开
Listen, we've got to finish this conversation.
听我说 我们必须把话谈完
Where's he going?
他要开去哪?
OK, look at me. Last clue for all the points.
好的 看着我 剩下分数的最后线索
Everyone wants to walk on me, but only a happy few ever have.
人人都想踏上我 但只有少数幸运儿办到
Take your time.
慢慢想
- Hey, bud. - Shh! Mom, it's the game. I'm trying to think.
- 嘿 小鬼头 - 嘘! 妈 在玩游戏 我拼命在想呢
- Sorry. Hey, Frank. How are you today? - Well, Mrs Billings.
- 对不起嘛! 法兰克 你今天好吗? - 很好 毕林斯太太
- Can I team up with Mom? - I don't know. It's not in the rules.
- 我可以跟我妈一组吗? - 不知道 规则上没定
Come on. What's the point in having rules if you can't bend 'em?
拜托 要是不懂得变通 订规则有何意义呢?
- OK. Just this once. - Yeah!
- 好吧 下不为例 - 耶!
All right. Give me some clues.
好了 给我些线索
It's round, but not always around. It's light sometimes, dark sometimes, or both.
圆的 但不一定在 有时亮 有时暗 或两者皆是
Everyone wants to walk on it, but only a happy few ever have.
人人都想踏上我 但只有少数幸运儿办到
- That is a hard one. - Tell me about it.
- 这题满难的 - 告诉我答案吧
- The moon! - Correct.
- 月亮! - 正确
Good job. All right. Come on.
干的好 好了 快点
- See you Monday. - Bye, Frank. Thanks.
- 周一见 - 拜 法兰克 谢啦
- Keep your snacks in the kitchen. - Bye, Mom.
- 你的点心在厨房里 - 拜 妈
He's really taken to you in the month you've been with us.
你跟我们在一起的这个月 他真的很喜欢你
- Likewise. - Too bad you can't stay on when Tony's back.
- 彼此 - 可惜东尼一回来 你就不能留下了
It was just a favour. I don't usually do this sort of ajob.
只是帮忙一下 我通常不接这种工作
I thought you were a professional driver.
我还以为你是职业驾驶
A different kind of driving.
不同性质的驾驶
Well, we're all gonna miss you when you're gone.
你不在 我们都会想念你的
And...
还有...
thank you for what you did.
谢谢你做的事
For what?
为了什么?
For turning the car around so that Jack wouldn't have to see us fighting.
把车子转过头去 杰克才不必见到我们夫妻吵架
- You really know kids, don't you? - I know fighting.
- 你真的很懂小孩 对不对? - 我懂得吵架
He hasn't seen Jack in months,
他好几个月没见到杰克
and when he gets back, all I hear is what I'm doing wrong.
结果一回来 只听到他在责骂我
You'd think that after being separated for a year that he would...
原以为分居一年后他会...
I'm sorry. You don't have to hear this.
对不起 你不必听这些的
It's OK. For what it's worth, I think you're doing a greatjob with Jack.
没关系 值得的是 我认为杰克你照顾的很好
Thank you.
谢谢
Any time I can be of help, if there's anything you need.
有何需要帮忙的话 随时都能找我
That's really sweet of you, Frank.
你人真好 法兰克
I might have to take you up on it.
这句话我可能得好好利用了
I almost forgot. I'm supposed to take Jack to the doctor tomorrow morning for a checkup,
我差点忘了 我明早应该载杰克 去给医生健康检查一下
but I'm organising a party for him, even though his birthday's not until next week.
但我在帮他筹办个派对 虽然下周才是他的生日
So, while I decorate and his friends arrive, I was thinking, if you wouldn't mind...
当我在布置和迎接他的朋友到来时 我想说 若你不介意的话...
- I'll take him. - I feel funny cutting into your weekend.
- 我会载他去的 - 打扰到你的周末真不好意思
I'm just picking up a friend at the airport later on in the day.
我只是那天稍晚 要去机场接个朋友而已
- That's nice. - What is?
- 不错嘛 - 怎么说?
The guys on security say you're a bit of a loner. Um...
保全的人说你有点独来独往...
- So it's just nice to hear you have a friend. - He's not really a friend.
- 只是很高兴听见你有朋友 - 他不太算是朋友
He's French.
他是法国人
I'll call you back.
回头再打给你
Audrey. I'd like to finish our conversation.
奥黛莉 我想把我们的话说完
If anything comes up before then, you have my cell.
要是十点前有任何变卦 就打我手机
- Nothing will come up, Mrs Billings. - Audrey.
- 不会有变卦的 毕林斯太太 - 叫我奥黛莉吧
Audrey.
奥黛莉
- Yeah, hello? - Confirmed for tomorrow. 9am.
- 喂? - 确定明天上午九点
Tomorrow, 9:00 am. Only change, the driver'll be taking him, not the mother.
天上午九点 唯一有变的 是由司机载他 不是母亲
Even better.
那更好
Vasily?
维斯利?
- Is it stable? - Yes, it's stable.
- 稳定吗? - 是的 很稳定
And the antidote?
解毒剂呢?
See you tomorrow.
明天见了
The drug-enforcement ministers of six Latin American countries
六名拉丁美洲国家的 药品管制局局长
arrived in Miami for a summit meeting...
抵达迈阿密参加高峰会议...
Yeah. Martin, Frank. 1156 Palmeadow.
对 法兰克马汀 帕草地街1156号
I'm waiting for an express delivery. That's what you told me 45 minutes ago.
我在等你们的外送 你们45分钟前也这么说
I don't need anything else. Just the pizza.
我不需要别的 只要披萨就好
- I'm not paying for that... - Hi.
- 我不会付... - 嗨
Hi.
嗨
So, it's one medium pie, no mozzarella, extra olives and extra anchovies,
因此是中型披萨 不加干酪 多加了橄榄和鳀鱼
which amounts to $11.95.
一共是11.95美元
- I hope you're hungry. - You have no idea.
- 希望您饿了 - 这可难说呢
I apologise for the delay, sir.
很抱歉延误送达 先生
Mrs Billings.
毕林斯太太
Audrey. Audrey.
奥黛莉 奥黛莉
- What are you doing? - What does it look like I'm doing?
- 你在干嘛? - 我样子像在干嘛?
- Have you been drinking? - A little.
- 你喝醉了吗? - 一点点
You said if I needed anything.
你说过我有何需要的话...
- I can't. - Why? Because of who I am?
- 不行 - 为什么? 因为我的身份吗?
Because of who I am.
是因为我的身份
I feel so lost. So confused.
我觉得好迷惘 好困惑
Who isn't?
谁不是呢?
Thank you, Frank.
谢谢你 法兰克
For the time and...
多谢你的拨空以及...
your respect.
你的尊重
I think it's what I needed the most.
我想那才是我最需要的
Bye.
拜
- Am I gonna get a shot? - I don't know.
- 要打针吗? - 我不知道
- Jeez. We're not open yet. - I need to see the doctor immediately.
- 老天 我们还没营业呢 - 很紧急 我需要立刻见医生
Right. Dr Koblin, if you'll come out here, please. We have an issue.
好 柯布林医生 麻烦您过来 这儿有个病人
You'll have to state the medical problem.
你必须叙述一下你的生理毛病
Actually, my problem's not medical. It's psychological.
事实上 我的毛病不是生理上的 是心理上的
Yes, Laura. What seems to be the problem?
萝拉 毛病是什么?
Me.
我
I hate shots.
我讨厌打针
Number one, there's no guarantee you're getting a shot.
第一点 你不一定要打针
There's no sense getting worked up over something that might not happen.
因此没必要杞人忧天
- Give me the news. - Doctor said I'm cured.
- 给我说好消息 - 医生说我痊愈了
- Frank, it hurts a lot. - I'd never let anyone hurt you a lot.
- 法兰克 打针很痛耶 - 我绝不会让任何人伤害你的
- Promise? - You know my fourth rule?
- 你保证? - 知道我的第四条规矩吗?
Never make a promise you can't keep. Come on.
绝不做无法遵守的承诺 来吧
Close the door.
关门
Come on.
快点
- May I help you? - Jack Billings to see Dr Koblin.
- 有何效劳呢? - 杰克毕林斯来见柯布林医生
He's out sick today. He'll be seeing Dr Tyberg.
抱歉 他今天请病假 他要去看泰勃医生
- I like Dr Koblin. - Don't worry. Dr Tyberg's very nice.
- 我喜欢柯布林医生 - 别担心 泰勃医生人非常好
Just take him into room 3.
带他去三号房吧
- Where's Laura? - Who?
- 萝拉在哪里? - 谁?
- You're standing at her desk. - That Laura. She's out sick too.
- 你站在她的位置上 - 那个萝拉喔 她也请病假了
There's a lot of flu going around. Now, come on. Doctor's got a busy day.
最近流行性感冒盛行 快点 医生很忙呢
Come on. It'll be over before you know it.
来吧 一下子就看完了
Hey, hey!
嘿 嘿!
I'm Dr Tyberg.
我是泰勃医生
Can't I wait for my doctor?
我不能等我的医生来再看吗?
Your doctor was called away on an emergency.
很遗憾 你的医生接到急诊外出
- The nurse said he had the flu. - That was the emergency.
- 护士说他得了感冒 - 那就是急诊啊
He came down with flu, very quickly. So, the sooner we start, the sooner we finish.
他突然染上了感冒 我们越早开始就越早结束
Come. I show you something very cool.
来 我带你看样非常酷的东西
I'm sorry. Doctor-patient privacy in room.
不好意思 医生病患之间的隐密空间
You can wait in reception area, or glass of water, or...
你可以在接待区等候 或去喝杯水 或者...
Hey, trust me. I am doctor.
嘿 信任我 我是医生
Please. It's phone.
请 你有电话
- Yeah? - All? all? Frank? I am here.
- 喂? - 喂喂? 法兰克? 我到了
- You're early. - Yeah, we had fantastic tailwinds.
- 你提早到了 - 对 碰到顺风
Put two hours on my vacation, just like that.
让我的假期多出了两小时 就那样
From now on, it's the only way I'm flying. Tailwinds or nothing.
从现在起 要我搭飞机 不是顺风就免谈
Glad you made it.
很庆幸你没挂
Hello. Sorry, Dr Dunietz is not in today. Call back Monday.
你好 抱歉 杜尼兹医生今天不在 周一再打来吧
I'm a little tied up. You mind taking a cab? You have the address, yes?
我有点走不开 你搭计程车好吗? 你有我地址的 对吧?
Oh, thank you. I heard the fish down here is fantastic. I could make us a bouillabaisse.
谢谢 我听说这儿的鱼肉很美味 我可以替我们煮锅法式海龙皇汤
You like bouillabaisse, Frank, no?
你喜欢法式海龙皇汤吧 法兰克?
I gotta go.
我得挂断了
Frank!
法兰克!
Maybe we'll wait for his regular doctor.
也许我们等 他固定看诊的医生回来吧
It's important that he receives immunisations.
接种疫苗是很重要的
- I'm sure. But a week won't make a difference. - No, we're doing it now.
- 当然 不过等个一星期没什么差别 - 不 我们现在就要注射
Get going, Jack!
继续走 杰克!
Look at me. Look at me.
看着我 看着我
- Remember my promise? - Yes.
- 记得我的承诺吗? - 记得
- It's... It's me! - Get out!
- 是...是我! - 出去!
Frank.
法兰克
Shit.
可恶
The patient's not cooperating. Prep the vehicle.
病人不合作 准备安装车辆
Come on, hurry.
快点 快
Don't worry. Everything's gonna be OK.
别担心 一切会没事的
- Freeze! Put your guns on the ground! - Get down!
- 不准动! 把枪放在地上! - 趴下!
- Si. - They got away.
- 说吧 - 他们逃掉了
- Cazzo! - Plan B?
- 干! - B计划?
Yes. Plan B.
是的 B计划
Oh, you made it.
哦 你赶来了
- Oh, what's that? - Jack's birthday present.
- 什么东西? - 杰克的生日礼物
Baseball uniform, cleats, glove and a bat.
棒球衣 球鞋 手套和球棒
- It's his favourite sport. - It was. Last year.
- 他最喜欢的运动 - 以前是 去年吧
He's on a soccer team now. He's good.
他现在进足球队 踢的不错
- You know, you should see him sometime. - Hello.
- 你应该有空多看看他 - 你好
- Mr and Mrs Billings! They're coming! - Hide, everyone. Hide!
- 毕林斯夫妇! 他们来了! - 快躲 大家躲起来!
- Yes. - Good morning, Mr Driver.
- 喂 - 早安 司机先生
- Who is this? - Look in your rear-view mirror and you'll see.
- 你是哪位? - 看看你的后照镜就知道了
I know what you're thinking. Bulletproof glass.
我晓得你在想什么 防弹玻璃
So tell me, in your experience which judging from the performance you put on in the office
所以依你的经验中告诉我 根据你在诊所里的表现
goes way beyond driving children to school
远远超乎了载送小孩上学
does bulletproof glass stop a 7.62 armour-piercing round?
防弹玻璃能挡得住 7.62厘米的穿甲弹吗?
Frank, why have you stopped the car?
法兰克 你为何停车呢?
Don't look, they are triangulated over 300 feet away.
不用看了 他们分布三边 在三百尺远的地方
Frank, pick up.
法兰克 快接呀
You screwed up my plan. I am going to tell you how to set things right.
你砸了我的计划 我要告诉你如何挽救
Someone is going to appear in a few seconds.
几秒钟后会有人出现
Let her in.
让她上车
Driver.
司机
Good boy. Good boy.
乖孩子呀乖孩子
Hi.
嗨
Leave it on.
扣着吧
Personally, I hate kids. I don't know what your feelings are on the subject,
我个人讨厌小孩 我不清楚你这方面感觉如何
but if you ever want to have any, make no moves but the moves I tell you to make.
但如果你还想有感觉的话 就别轻举妄动
You're in her hands now. They can be gentle hands, but they can be the hands from hell.
你现在落入她手中 他们可以温文儒雅 也可以心狠手辣
- Trust me on this one. - Trust him on this one.
- 相信我说的话 - 相信他说的话
Now, drive.
现在 开车吧
Make a left.
左转
I said left.
我说左转
Listen, we keep doing this your way, they're gonna catch us.
听我说 照你的方式继续下去 他们会追上我们的
- Do this my way, no one gets hurt. - Where's the fun in that?
- 照我的方式做 没人会受伤 - 那样子有何乐趣呢?
Let's save the fun for later.
乐趣留到以后吧
Hey!
嘿! 小心
Not bad.
技术不赖嘛
Didn't your mother teach you to say thank you?
你母亲没教你要说谢谢吗?
She tried, and failed miserably.
她试过 可惜失败了
- I think we lost them. - Think again.
- 我想我们甩掉他们了 - 再想一遍吧
Thought complete. Let's go.
想完了 走吧
You can't find him? He's one man in one car. He's a chauffeur, for chrissakes.
找不到他? 他开着一辆车 拜托 他只是名司机啊
Not exactly, sir. There's a possibility he was in on it.
不一定 先生 有可能他也有参与
- That's impossible. - How would you know?
- 不可能 - 你怎会知道?
He could have been setting this up the whole time, and you wouldn't have known.
他在这工作了一个月 可能这段期间 都在设计此事你也不晓得
- And you are an expert on knowing people. - His background.
- 你真是识人一流的专家唷 - 他的背景资料
He's ex-Special Forces. Headed a commando unit. Specialised in search and destroy.
他是前特种部队人员 突击队单位 专长是搜索和破坏
Been in and out of Lebanon, Syria, Sudan. The man is a hunter.
曾经进出过黎巴嫩 叙利亚 苏丹 这人是个猎人
I don't care what his skills are or where he's from.
我不管他有何专长或来自哪里
This is not a war zone, this is an American city!
这儿不是战场 这是美国城市!
Where's my son?
我的儿子在哪?
Last stop. All out.
终点站 通通下车
You're quite a guy. Another time, another place...
你真有男子气概 假时假地...
you and me, baby, the pleasure we could have.
你和我 宝贝 我们可以很爽的
Beauty.
漂亮
Frank.
法兰克
Frank!
法兰克!
Not what you expected when you reported for work this morning, is it, Frank? No?
跟你今早预计的工作内容不一样 是不是啊 法兰克?
Is that what passes for wit in this circle?
在这圈子里就这么点聪明吗?
In this circle, my friend, wit is not a requirement of the job.
在这圈子里 我的朋友 聪明并非工作的需求资格
Brutality, yes. An ability to inflict pain, absolutely.
心狠手辣才是 手段凶残能力 绝对必备
A certain psychotic, moral ignorance, blind obedience, all required.
丧心病狂 道德泯灭 盲目服从 全都需要
- But not wit. How was it? - Fun.
- 但绝非聪明! 怎样? - 好玩
Only the beginning, my love.
这仅是开端 亲爱的
- What's this all about? - A timely question.
- 这是怎么回事? - 问的刚刚好
Max.
麦克斯
Pardon me.
恕我失陪
- Hello. - Put me on the speaker.
- 喂 - 接到扩音机上
In the next two hours, you'll get five million dollars in $100 bills.
两小时后 筹五百万元 以百元钞票装
Put them in a waterproof suitcase, go to the Bayfront Park, personally.
放进防水手提箱内 你亲自提到湾前公园
There will be a blue Chrysler parked there. Place the suitcase in the trunk, and leave.
那边会停着一辆蓝色克莱斯勒车子 把手提箱放进后车厢后离开
I don't know if I can get five million dollars in two hours.
我不清楚两小时内 筹不筹得到五百万
I read the newspapers. When you were appointed to your current position,
我读过报纸的 当你被任命你目前的职位
your net worth exceeded 100 million dollars, so you won't even feel the bite.
你的净值收入就超过一百万美元 所以对你根本是九牛一毛
What guarantee do I have that you won't harm my son?
我有何保证 你不会伤害我儿子呢?
Guarantee? Mr Billings, I am not a car dealer.
保证? 毕林斯先生 我不是车商
Don't let the charming accent and my impeccable syntax mislead you.
别让这迷人的口音 和我无懈可击的语法误导了你
I live in the jungle, and in the jungle you either eat or be eaten.
我住在丛林里 而在丛林里 不是吃人就是被吃
But, in the spirit of business, here is the guarantee.
但是 本着商场精神 保证如下:
Ten minutes past the deadline, if the money doesn't arrive, I send a finger.
超过底限十分钟后 如果钱还没送到 我会送一根指头
20 minutes, a hand. 30 minutes, a foot.
二十分钟后 送一只手 三十分钟后 送一只脚
Sounds like we have a deal.
听起来我们条件谈成了
You have a deal.
一言为定
Could we please speak to our son?
可以让我们跟我们儿子讲话吗?
Mommy! Mommy!
妈咪! 妈咪!
You have two hours, Mr Billings. Starting now.
你有两小时时间 毕林斯先生 现在开始计时
- Just get my son! - All right. All right.
- 救出我儿子! - 好的 好的
Frank, you promised you wouldn't let anybody hurt me!
法兰克 你保证过 不会让任何人伤害我!
- You promised! - Never make promises you can't keep.
- 你保证过的! - 千万别下无法遵守的承诺
I don't. It's one of my rules.
我不会 这是我的原则之一
Wow.
喔
Bravo. A man who leads his life by rules. In my world rules are meant to be broken.
好呀 一个生活有原则的男人 在我的世界中 原则就是用来打破的
- Not mine. - You're gonna have to make an exception.
- 我的可不行 - 你不得不破个例了
Go.
走吧
Prego.
请
- Go. - Hey, driver!
- 走 - 嘿 司机!
No, no, wait, wait. A little distance between us isn't a bad thing.
不 不 等等 等等 我们之间保持点距离不是坏事
Andiamo!
快!
Now.
现在
Hold on. The signal.
等等 讯号
- Hello. - It's me.
- 你好 - 是我
- You son of a bitch. - Look, I had nothing to do with this.
- 你这婊养的 - 听着 我和这事毫无关连
- One scratch on his head... - Let me speak to who's in charge.
- 他若少根寒毛... - 让我跟负责人讲话
- This is US Marshal Stappleton. - Act fast. There are three boats.
- 我是史坦雷顿警官 - 行动要快 有三艘船
- Tell us where you are. - Get a plane. They're heading north.
- 告诉我们你的位置 - 弄辆飞机 他们朝北边去了
- Tell me where you are. - Just tell us where you are!
- 告诉我们你的位置 - 告诉我们你的位置!
Hello, Frank?
喂 法兰克?
Got it.
锁定了
- All? - Tarconi, it's me. Get out of the house.
- 喂? - 塔科尼 是我 快离开房子
- I was just putting the madeleines... - Forget the madeleines, just get out.
- 不行 我才刚摆玛德琳蛋糕进去烤... - 别管玛德琳蛋糕了 离开就是
- And go where? - Anywhere. Go to the beach.
- 去哪? - 哪里都行 去海滩吧
Oh, the beach. The famous Miami Beach.
喔 海滩哟 著名的迈阿密海滩
Oh, my dream. I would love to go to the beach.
我梦寐以求呢 我很想去海滩
Maybe not.
也许不
- Freeze! Who the fuck are you? - I'm the cook.
- 不准动! 你他妈的是谁? - 我是厨师
Oh. This is a mistake. A terrible mistake.
这是误会啦 天大的误会
Why we can't all just get along, you know?
我们为何不能和平相处呢?
- Hello. - It's Frank. Pretend it's someone else.
- 你好 - 我是法兰克 假装是别人打来的
Hi, Susan.
嗨 苏珊
No, I'm just here at home.
不 我刚到家
I didn't do it, Audrey. She had a gun on Jack. I had no choice.
不是我干的 奥黛莉 她枪抵着杰克 我别无选择
Yeah, I saw that. What do you know?
嗯 我看到了 你知道什么?
- It's more than a kidnapping. - They asked for a ransom.
- 目的不光是绑架而已 - 他们有要求赎金啊
The doctors, they were fake. They were trying to give Jack a shot. When I interrupted them...
医生全是假的 我闯进去时 他们正想给杰克打针...
I promised Jack I wouldn't let anyone hurt him. I'm not gonna break that promise.
我答应过杰克不会让任何人伤害他 我不会违背誓言的
- Frank. - I'll call you back.
- 法兰克 - 我再打给你
Audrey.
奥黛莉
- Is everything all right? - That's a pretty stupid question to ask, Jeff.
- 一切没问题吧? - 你问这问题相当愚蠢 杰夫
All right. So tell me again, Inspector Tarconi,
好了 再跟我说一遍 塔科尼警官
why you didn't immediately identify yourself as a police officer.
你为何没立即表明 自己是警务人员身份?
Oh, I was overwhelmed by the effectiveness of your operation,
喔 我被你们的行动效率吓呆了
the sophistication of your equipment.
你们的装备精良先进
You know, I work in a small office in a small town. We only have small crimes.
我在小地方的小警局里任职 只有零星犯罪事件
- I was a little insecure. - You and Frank Martin are friends, right?
- 我有点不保险 - 你和法兰克马汀是朋友 对吧?
A friend? Oh, I wouldn't say exactly a friend. I know him, we have a relationship.
朋友? 也称不上是朋友啦 我认识他 我们之间有种关系
A long relationship?
长期关系?
- Not so long. - They found you cooking in his house.
- 不是很久 - 他们发现你在他房子里作菜啊
- I'm French! - So?
- 我是法国人! - 那又怎样?
We don't need to know someone a long time in order to cook for them. It's an icebreaker.
我们不需要认识很久才能下厨 那是促进情感的方式
Take, for example, this sandwich and coffee you so graciously offer me.
就拿你好心给我 三明治和咖啡的例子来说吧
Well, pardon me to think so, but it's not very good.
恕我无礼 但这难吃的要命
I know, but what has that got to do with anything?
我知道是很难吃 不过有何关连呢?
Do you have a kitchen?
你们有厨房吗?
Stay back. Stay back.
退后 退后
Don't move. Smith!
别动! 史密斯!
Drop it.
放下
Oh, Jesus. What happened?
天啊 发生了什么事?
We'll take care of it for you.
我们会帮你医好的
- Is this safe? - Look over your shoulder.
- 你确定这安全吗? - 朝你肩膀看过去
We got you covered.
团团掩护着你
As my mother used to say, a meal is only limited by your imagination.
我母亲以前常说 餐点仅局限于你的想像力
- Creme brulee et croque monsieur. - Cream brulee?
- 火腿乳酪三明治 - 奶油三明治?
- Creme brulee. - Cock?
- 乳酪三明治 - 乳奶?
- Croque monsieur. - Croque monsieur.
- 火腿乳酪三明治 - 火腿乳酪三明治
- Oui? - Where are you?
- 喂? - 你在哪里?
- Cooking. - Cooking. Can you talk?
- 作菜 - 作菜 方便讲话吗?
- Oh, speak of the devil. My mother. - Mom.
- 说曹操曹操就到 是我母亲 - 妈
Please, do you mind?
麻烦一下 不介意吧?
Thank you.
谢谢
Oui, Maman. Je suis tres bien arrive?
是的 妈 我已经到了
Oui, tres tres bien, merci. Oui. Ah, oui, c'est une tres jolie ville.
对 非常非常好 谢谢 啊 对 这座城市非常漂亮
- May I ask who you're cooking for? - For the US marshals.
- 可以问你在替谁作菜吗? - 替美国警官们
Once they found my badge, they were very polite. They gave me a coffee and a sandwich.
他们一发现我的警徽就变得彬彬有礼 还递给我咖啡和三明治
You wouldn't believe what passes for food here.
你不会相信这儿的食物有多糟
I am correcting the situation while they wait for my chief to call and confirm everything.
趁他们等我局长来电证实一切时 我在修正这种情况
Of course, that might take a while. He's never there.
当然 可能要花一阵子 他不在那儿
- Anything about me? - They are very interested about you.
- 有提到我吗? - 有的 他们对你非常感兴趣
They want to know where you are. Where are you?
他们想知道你在哪里 你在哪里?
Nowhere for very long. Listen, hold on.
老早就不知身在何处了 听着 别挂断
(上锁)
Do you have access to a computer?
你可以使用电脑吗?
Easier than having access to something decent to eat.
比吃到正经食物还容易
- Oh, handsome fellow. Who is he? - Do they have an ID program?
- 帅小子 他是谁? - 我正想知道 有身份识别程式吗?
Forgive me. I'm not so used to this system. At home, there is one computer for ten of us.
抱歉 我不太习惯这系统 在老家 我们十个人才配给一台电脑
So, how is it with you, Frank?
你的情况怎样 法兰克?
- It's a complicated story. - Ah, you mean you are in the shit?
- 说来复杂 - 你是指你踩到狗屎了?
- You might say that. - In other words, your natural state.
- 可以那么说 - 换句话说 你早习以为常了
Voil?
有了
A Russian biologist with advanced degrees from the state laboratory.
俄罗斯生物学家 具有官方实验室高等学位
- Do we have an address? - Miami, Boca West, King Street, number 11.
- 有地址吗? - 迈阿密波卡西区国王街11号
Get out!
滚开!
Hey!
嘿!
- What are you doing? - Trying to catch a bus.
- 你想干嘛? - 想赶搭公车
Come on.
快点
What are you doing, driver? Not so good on the water, hey?
你在干嘛呀 司机? 在水上技术不太好吗?
Stop it! Stop it!
停啦! 停啦!
- OK. OK. - Tell me about the doctor's office.
- 好的 好的 - 跟我说说医生诊疗室的事
- What doctor's office? - Where you tried to stick the kid with this.
- 什么医生诊疗室? - 你们想用这注射那孩子的地方
You want to tell me?
想告诉我吗?
Do you know what you have done? Do you know what you have done?
你知道你干了什么好事吗? 你知道你干了什么好事吗?
Obviously something not conducive to your good health, which is all I needed to know.
显然是无益健康 也是我需要知道的事
Have a good life...
好好享受美好人生...
what's left of it.
仅剩的时日吧
- Outpost to base. The ransom is still there. - Thanks.
- 前哨回报基地 赎金还在原地 - 谢谢
The ransom hasn't been picked up.
赎金还没被取走
- Don't worry. - What if it's notjust a kidnapping?
- 别担心 - 万一不光是绑架那么简单呢?
- I've worked on many kidnapping cases. - If they don't take it I won't get my son back.
- 我处理过无数绑架案件 - 他们不取赎金 我儿子是不是就回不来?
Don't make this any more complicated than it is.
别让此事更加复杂了
I'm not making this complicated, Jefferson. It's because of yourjob.
我没使它复杂 杰佛逊 是因为你工作的关系
- What does my job have to do with this? - It has everything to do with it.
- 我的工作和此事有何关系? - 完全有关系
Because you became famous, we became the targets.
你不懂吗? 因为你出名了 我们便成为标靶
No matter what you think, the only one who's out there trying to get Jack back is Frank.
不管你们怎么想 外面想救杰克回来的只有法兰克
- The chauffeur? - You spoke to Frank Martin?
- 那个司机? - 你跟法兰克马汀讲过话?
- What the hell are you doing talking to him? - He's the last person who saw Jack alive!
- 你到底干嘛跟他讲话? - 他是最后一个看见杰克活着的人!
We've found the boy.
找到男孩了
Hard drive blew.
硬碟爆了
- Get another one in there. - Yes, sir.
- 再拿一个装进去 - 是 先生
- How long is it gonna take? - Ma'am, we're going as fast as we can.
- 这要花多久时间? - 夫人 我们会尽快的
- He can suffocate in there. - Stay calm.
- 他会闷死在里面 - 保持镇静
- It's my son! - Let them work.
- 是我儿子呀! - 让他们做事吧
- Are you gonna sit and do nothing? - They're experts.
- 你光会坐着什么也不做吗? - 他们是专家呀
Everyone is an expert! I've had it with all of you!
人人都是专家! 我受够你们所有人了!
Audrey!
奥黛莉!
Mommy!
妈咪!
Jack!
杰克!
Are you OK?
你不要紧吧?
There you go, little buddy.
好了 小子
Breathe. Come on, breathe.
呼吸呀 快点呼吸
- You're the devil. - I wish.
- 你真是恶魔 - 但愿如此
- Shit! Dimitri, you scare shit in me. - Where is Sonovitch?
- 可恶! 狄米崔 你吓死我了 - 索诺维契在哪里?
- In chamber. - I need to speak with him.
- 在小房间里 - 我需要马上找他谈
Sit down! Listen Panasonic. Is rap music, is good.
坐下! 听听Panasonic 是饶舌音乐 很不错的
- What was that? - I don't know.
- 怎么回事? - 不知道
Shit!
可恶!
- What are you doing? - I need antidote.
- 你进来干嘛? - 我需要解毒剂
The driver, he inject me with virus. Look!
那司机给我注射了病毒 你看!
- Dimitri, where would he get the virus? - The one we left in doctor's surgery.
- 狄米崔 他从哪弄到病毒的? - 我们掉在医生诊疗室的那支
Please, I need antidote. I am sick.
求求你 我需要解毒剂 我生病了
Calm down. You're not sick. You have four hours before the virus is active.
冷静点 你没生病 病毒生效前你还有四小时
You know that. You worked on creating it.
你知道的 你有参与研发的啊
- Open fridge. - I'm telling you...
- 冰箱打开 - 我告诉你...
lzvinite. Open fridge. Open the fridge!
对不起 冰箱打开 冰箱打开!
Yes. Insurance policy. How many you have?
没错 保险策略 你有多少?
Two doses. Enough for Tipov and myself.
两剂 够提巴夫和我自己用
Tipov's policy cancelled. There is one for me.
提巴夫的策略取消了 一剂给我
And I want it now. Come on.
我现在就要 快点
Come on. Let's do it!
快点 动手吧!
- Let's not. - Who are you?
- 休想 - 你是谁?
- There is enough for two. - You don't need it.
- 够两人用 - 你不需要
- But you injected me. - With water.
- 但你给我注射了呀 - 里头是水
- I'm not sick. - You're not sick.
- 我没生病? - 你没生病
- Water. - Water.
- 水? - 水
Son of bitch!
王八蛋!
Good. Our problem is solved. One dose for each of us.
很好 我们的问题解决了 我们一人一剂
- It's not for us. - One for you and one for the child. Touching.
- 不是给我们 - 一剂给你 一剂给那孩子 真令人感动
My patience is about to run out.
我的耐性快用完了
- Tell me about the virus. - OK. What do you want know?
- 告诉我病毒的事 - 好 你想知道些什么?
Everything. What is it?
一切 怎么发生的?
A recombinant retroimmune double-polymorphing effluent.
释放出一种重新组合的 免疫退化同质多晶型体
The child will die. Anyone he breathes on will die, and then it's over.
那孩子会死 任何呼吸到 他喘息的人也会死 然后就结束了
- What do you mean, ''It's over?'' - The virus goes inert after 24 hours.
- 你说"结束"是什么意思? - 病毒入侵24小时后死亡
Thanks for the lesson. Now give me the vials.
多谢你的讲解 现在把瓶子给我
You really want to play superhero, don't you? Well, let's see if you can fly.
你真想扮超级英雄 是不是? 那就看看你会不会飞了
- You OK? - I'm OK.
- 你不要紧吧? - 不要紧
There's nothing to worry about. It's just a simple viral infection combined with stress.
没什么好担心的 只是轻微的传染病加上压力所致
It should pass in a day or two. I gave him something to help him sleep.
应该过个一两天就会好的 我给他开点药方帮助他睡觉
- Call me if anything arises. - Thank you, Doctor.
- 病情若有变化再通知我 - 谢谢你 医生
You know, Audrey, all this has...
奥黛莉 这件事...
well, it's made me realise what a fool I've been.
令我明了到我过去有多混帐
With Jack...
对杰克...
and with you.
以及对你
- Are you OK? - Mr Billings. We're running late.
- 你没事吧? - 毕林斯先生 我们要迟到了
I'll be right out. I'd like to come by after the conference,
我马上出去 开完会之后我再过来
check on Jack.
看看杰克
Check on you.
看看你
Good. I'll see you soon.
很好 晚点见了
They're here if you need them.
有事的话 门外有警卫
- Are you all right, ma'am? - I'm fine.
- 你还好吧 夫人? - 我很好
- Hello. - It's me.
- 你好 - 是我
- Are you OK? - Go to your bedroom.
- 没事吧? - 回你卧房
Hi, Susan. How are you?
嗨 苏珊 你好吗?
I'm alone. Where are you, Frank?
我现在一个人了 你在哪 法兰克?
Turn around.
转身
Frank, you were wrong. It was a kidnapping. Jack is fine.
法兰克 你错了 只是绑架而已 杰克好端端的
Jack's been infected with a virus. Anyone who comes into contact with him will die.
杰克已经感染了病毒 凡是接触到他的人都会死
What are you telling me?
你在说什么啊?
- Are you telling me my son is gonna die? - No, he's not.
- 你是在说我儿子会死吗? - 不 他不会
Once incubated, the virus becomes airborne, so anyone he breathes on gets infected.
一旦潜伏体内 病毒便利用空气传播 所以任何呼吸到的人也会感染上
Your son was a weapon. The target is his father.
你儿子是武器 目标是他父亲
- Jefferson? Well, why? - The conference. It's the only logical answer.
- 杰佛逊? 为什么? - 会议是唯一合乎逻辑的答案
Every drug-enforcement agency in one room.
各个药品管制局机关人员齐聚一堂
Your husband breathes, the room dies.
你的丈夫一呼吸 整个房间的人都会死
You gotta trust me, Audrey.
你得信任我 奥黛莉
Can you get to him?
你能连络上他吗?
- What are you gonna do? - Find the guy responsible.
- 你要怎么做? - 找出该负责的家伙
He has more of this. For you and everybody else.
他有更多解毒剂 可供你和其他人用
For you now.
也为了你
We have a guest.
有人闯入了
- You're burning up. - I'm OK.
- 你发烧了 - 我不要紧
You gotta go. Go.
你得走了 走吧
Don't move!
别动!
- Is the governor here? - Everybody's here.
- 首长来了吗? - 大家都会来
Delegates from all over the world.
来自全球各地的代表
- Just a second. Hello. - Jefferson, you can't go to the conference.
- 稍等一下 喂 - 杰佛逊 你不能参加会议
- Is everything all right? - To give him a deadly virus...
- 一切可好? - 给他一种致命的病毒...
- I can't hear you. I'm inside. - I've got it, and so do you.
- 我听不见你 我在室内 - 既然我听的到 你也一样
- I can't hear you. - Their plan is to infect everyone there.
- 我听不见你 - 他们计划感染那儿的每个人
- I'm gonna have to call you back. - Jeff!
- 我回头再给你电话 - 杰夫!
Mr Billings, are you all right?
毕林斯先生 你不要紧吧?
- I'm all right. Come on, let's go. - You sure?
- 不要紧 快点 我们走吧 - 你确定?
- All? - You still a guest of the government?
- 喂? - 你还在当政府座上佳宾啊?
They gave me the five-star accommodation. Let me guess you need my help.
他们给了我五星级的食宿 让我猜一下 你需要我的帮助
Are you near the computer?
你离电脑近吗?
It's practically my pillow. So, how do you want to start?
差不多算是我的枕头了 你想如何着手?
- I don't know. I have nothing. - Ah. My favourite type of investigation.
- 不知道 毫无头绪 - 我最喜爱的侦办类型
Let's see. Alors.
让我瞧瞧吧
I'd like to take this opportunity to introduce you to...
我想藉这个机会向各位介绍...
Breathe. That's right, breathe, my friend, breathe.
呼吸 没错 呼吸 我的朋友 呼吸
Once these bastards are out of the way
明天 一旦这些混蛋上了黄泉路
and their agreements are dead and buried, you know what the biggest problem will be?
他们的协议就会石沉大海 你知道最大的问题会是什么吗?
- What? - Counting the money.
- 什么? - 数钱啦
- I can't wait. - Ay-ay-ay!
- 我等不及明天了 - 哎呀呀
Aah. Gianni Chellini.
吉亚尼切里尼
Hires himself out to anyone looking to make trouble: Red Brigade, Shining Path.
受雇于任何想制造麻烦的人: 义大利红色旅 秘鲁光辉道路组织
Someone accessed a database on the 15th floor.
十五楼有人登入资料库
That's Gonzalez. He's on vacation.
是刚萨雷兹 他休假了
Was behind the hostage-taking of the OPEC ministers in Geneva.
幕后策划日内瓦 石油输出国家组织官员劫持人质事件
It was a nice piece of work.
那一票干的干净俐落
- Give me an address. - Miami, East Highland,
- 地址给我 - 迈阿密东高地区...
Pelican Drive, number 26900.
鹈鹕大道26900号
- We've found the car. - You're one great cop, Tarconi.
- 我们找到了车子 - 你是一流警察 塔科尼
Thank you for the compliment. Now I'm going back to sleep.
多谢你的赞美 现在我要去睡回笼觉了
Hm. Maybe not.
也许不
- Bumbaclaat, man! Move out the way! - Move over.
- 闪一边去 老兄! 让开! - 坐到一旁去
I'll do ya!
我会...乖乖照做
Mommy.
妈咪
- Honey. You feeling better? - A little bit.
- 甜心 你好点了吗? - 一点点
Why don't you try to go back to sleep, OK?
你何不再继续睡 好吗?
Ma'am, are you all right?
夫人 你没事吧?
Jefferson. Jefferson, are you OK?
杰佛逊 杰佛逊 你没事吧?
OK, do it.
好的 动手
- What are you doing? - You know, last night got me thinking.
- 你在做什么? - 昨晚我考虑过
How do we transport the antidote safely?
怎样安全运送解毒剂
We need something that won't break or can't be stolen.
我们需要不会打破 不会被偷
Something totally secure. Me.
彻底安全的东西 就是我
Impressive. Get dressed.
真厉害 去穿上衣服吧
Stop him.
阻止他
- These your friends? - Not yet.
- 这些是你朋友? - 还不是
- Where'd they go? - The garage.
- 他们跑去哪了? - 车库
- I'm out of ammo. - Me too.
- 我弹药打光了 - 我也一样
- So am I. - Where are the reloads?
- 我也是 - 弹药在哪里?
The garage.
车库
Check the house. Go, go, go!
检查房子 快快快!
Get him! Get him!
去抓他! 去抓他!
- What d'you want me to do? - Keep the meter running.
- 你要我怎么做? - 让车子保持发动
Bye. Don't worry, baby. You're safe now. You're safe.
拜 别担心 宝贝 你现在安全了 你安全了
You're so beautiful. Remind me of my yellow poom-poom rider.
你好美 令我想起了我的黄包车
Don't move.
别动
- Oh, Mr Driver. - I'll blow you into tomorrow.
- 司机先生 - 我会叫你脑袋开花
I'll bleed what you came for all over the floor. You wouldn't want this.
你来的目的是想教我血溅地板 你不会想这样吧?
Not after you worked so hard trying to get to the antidote.
在你这么卖命想取得解毒剂后 这样可行不通
Take a good look, Frank Martin.
好好瞧一下 法兰克马汀
I'm a cure for what ails you. I'm the only cure for what ails you.
我就是令你头疼的解药 唯一的解药
I am the antidote.
我就是解毒剂
Nice try. I'm impressed. I didn't give you enough credit.
干的不错 我很印象深刻 我不太相信你
- It took more than a driver to figure this out. - I haven't figured it all out yet.
- 一名司机是理解不出的 - 我还没完全理解
Perhaps I can help you. What part are you a little thick on?
或许我能帮忙你 你有哪部份搞不懂?
- You. Why? - Oh.
- 你 为什么? - 哇
That's the easy part. It's a business deal, pure and simple. I'm for hire to the highest bidder.
那部份很容易说明 纯粹是生意交易 谁出价最高 我就受雇于谁
In this case, the highest bidder was the Colombian cocaine cartels
在此例中 出价最高的是 哥伦比亚古柯碱毒枭
that wanted these pesky lawmen off their backs.
他们想除掉这些讨厌的执法者
You think killing politicians will make things easier for them?
你真以为杀死这些政客 他们运毒就会更容易吗?
That's not my problem. I was hired to do a job.
那不是我的问题 我是受雇办事的
I did the job, like you. Just my pay is better.
我完成了使命 像你一样 只不过我的酬劳比较优渥
My hair and my suit, too.
我的头发和西装也一样
Oh, Lola.
哦 萝拉
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have a plane to catch.
恕我失陪了 我有飞机要赶
Kill him.
杀了他
Ciao.
再见了
- Don't even blink. - What's in this for you?
- 别想眨一下眼 - 这事对你有何乐趣?
Pleasure...
乐趣...
in killing you.
就是杀你
We're coming live from the Key Biscayne causeway
我们现在从必士京跨海大桥 实况转播
where at least ten police cars are in hot pursuit of a stolen red pick-up truck.
至少有十辆警车正在全力追逐 一辆失窃的红色平板卡车
Oh, my. This is just nuts. Jim, are you getting that?
老天 真是有够疯的了 吉姆 你有拍到吗?
There's another car that is swaying past the police, as if they were standing still.
有另一辆车疾驶过警车 警车就好像静止不动似的
- Son of a bitch can drive. Whoo. - Yes, he can.
- 王八蛋真会开车呢 - 一点也没错
We have clearance for takeoff.
跑道已清除干净
Sit back, enjoy your flight, and we will be in Colombia before you know it.
坐下来好好享受你的飞行 不知不觉中我们就到哥伦比亚了
We have a problem with the landing gear. I need to land.
起落架出了毛病 我必须重新降落
- Can we fly with the problem? - Theoretically.
- 飞有问题吗? - 理论上是没有
Then you'll land when we get to Colombia.
那就飞到哥伦比亚再降落
Go and see if you can lift it manually.
去看看能不能手动收回来
Sorry for the inconvenience. Nothing to worry about.
抱歉造成你的不便 无需担心
Sorry, flight's been cancelled.
很抱歉 航班取消了
I'm sorry to inform you that you have been cancelled.
很抱歉通知你 你已经被取消了
Have a seat.
请坐
Relax.
放松
Drink something. Let's get to know each other.
喝点酒 我们彼此好好认识一下
I think I know everything I need to know.
我想我需要知道的都知道了
Shit.
可恶
Five points. What has eyes but no ears, skin but no hair,
答对得五分 什么东西 有眼睛却没耳朵 有皮肤却没头发
it's white inside and brown outside?
里面白色 外面棕色
- Mom? - A worm?
- 妈? - 虫子吗?
- Wrong. Dad? - A caterpillar.
- 错 爸? - 毛毛虫
- Wrong. - A potato.
- 错 - 马铃薯
- May I help you? - I was just leaving.
- 可以帮你吗? - 我正要离开
- Coconut. - Wrong.
- 椰子 - 错
- A snake. - Wrong.
- 蛇 - 错
- A peanut. - Yuck!
- 花生 - 不对!
- A hot dog. - Wrong.
- 热狗 - 错
- That was fast. - Yeah.
- 好快 - 对
- Didn't want you to miss your plane. - That's very thoughtful of you.
- 不希望你错过班机嘛 - 你真是体贴
Check it out, my man.
看一看 伙伴
You won't believe what happened to me last night.
你们不会相信我昨晚 经历了什么样的事
I have something for you. Since you never got to the beach.
我有东西要送你 因为你海滩没去成
Oh, you know, water's water, sand is sand. Here, there, it's all the same.
你知道的 水就是水 沙就是沙 这儿那儿还不都一样
Flight 069 to Paris.
飞往巴黎编号069班机
Thank you, Frank. It was an interesting vacation.
谢谢你 法兰克 真是有趣的假期
- What more could one ask for? - Ah, yeah.
- 还能奢求什么呢? - 是呀
- Au revoir, Frank. - Au revoir, my friend. Have a good flight.
- 再见了 法兰克 - 再见了 朋友 祝你一路顺风
I doubt it. They said it is all headwinds.
我很怀疑 听说全程是逆风
I guess we can't have everything we wish for, can we?
我猜我们无法事事如意 对吧?
No, we can't.
对 我们不行
Yeah.
嗯
I'm looking for a transporter.
我在找一位送货人
I'm listening.
请说